#### Contact

8779059463 (Mobile) tejasharne1996@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tejas-harne (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Java

C++

Python

### Languages

Marathi (Full Professional) English (Full Professional) Hindi (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Introduction to Big Data - Hadoop Cryptography Machine Learning

### Honors-Awards

You Make a Difference HP Think-a-Thon Winner Distinction

# Tejas Harne

Google | Flipkart | Oracle | BITS Pilani | Big Data and ML enthusiast Hyderabad

# Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Java, Python, C++, Data Structures & Algorithms, PL/SQL and J2EE. Strong engineering professional having Bachelor's Degree from Birla Institute of Technology and Science and graduated with 9.15 CGPA.

Enthusiastic about the Machine Learning and Big Data domain!

# Experience

Google Web Solutions Engineer II March 2020 - Present (6 months) Hyderabad, Telangana

# Flipkart

Software Development Engineer II January 2020 - March 2020 (3 months) Bengaluru Area, India

#### Oracle

2 years 7 months

Senior Applications Engineer December 2019 - December 2019 (1 month)

Hyderabad Area, India

### Applications Engineer II

June 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 7 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

- Received 'You Make a Difference' Award from Senior Vice President for ownership of several major projects in Oracle.
- Developed key Enterprise modules in Oracle Fusion Purchasing Cloud using a Java-Based Framework ADF (J2EE) under Agile/Scrum environment.

- Developed and designed the architecture for many RESTful and SOAP webservices for salient ERP functionalities.
- Acute focus on effective application performance with optimization of SQL Queries in Database.
- Involved in the design of robust and idempotent ESS services having high availability and scalability, with load balancing.
- Implemented automation for continuous validation of Business Logic using the JUnit Framework for quality assurance.
- Active Interactions with Clients and Product Managers to troubleshoot & debug technical issues and resolve code defects.

# Amazon

Summer Intern

January 2017 - June 2017 (6 months)

#### Qualcomm

Machine Learning Engineer

May 2016 - July 2016 (3 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Developed a dynamic power management system for Qualcomm Snapdragon octa-core processors

.

- Applied Machine Learning using 1-layer Deep Bidirectional Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) for Temperature Prediction of the cores in the CPU.
- Workload Classification of mobile applications (using Machine Learning KNN classifiers) and mitigating the workload in the best possible way to reduce the temperature of the core. (Python Libraries used for ML: Keras, Theano and Caffe)
- · Hosted weekly sessions for coaching team in Machine Learning

L&T Infotech

Application Developer

May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Developed a cross-platform app using Microsoft TouchDevelop.

- The technology used (Microsoft TouchDevelop) helped to create Cross Platform apps which reduces the no. of employees required to write a code for an app which is to be deployed in multiple platforms.
- Microsoft TouchDevelop, being a new technology, was put forth to the whole Business Unit (BU) spanning across almost all branches of L&T Infotech in India and also the technical host of an International Conference Call (USA) for presenting the app to the client.

# Education

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2013 - 2017)

MSAS, Navi Mumbai (2010 - 2012)